恶魔星系
The Satanic Nebula!
或者  去失落群星之湖
Or...the lagoon of lost stars...
再或者
or we could go...
去布莱顿[英国旅游胜地]
to Brighton!
博士与布莱顿的轶事
请见老版第15季和第18季前四集
我安排好了一整天的行程
I've got a whole day worked out.
抱歉  但你应该看得出来  我有约在身
Sorry, but as you can see, I've got plans.
是吗
Have you?
看看我
Look at me.
嗯挺好
Yeah, OK.
不对不对
No, no, no. No.
再看看
Look at me.
看着呢
Yep, looking.
不是吧你
Seriously?
你脸上涂这幺艷干什么
Why is your face all coloured in?
七点一刻  见我
7.15. Meeting me.
你来
You are.
约会
Date.
第二次
Second one.
话能说出口不容易
Got the words out.
虽然语序有点乱  但是  谁叫你教数学
Not in the right order, but, hey... maths teacher!
出去
Out!
你长高了吗
Are you taller?
高跟鞋
Heels.
怎么  高处架子上的东西够不着吗
What, do you have to reach a high shelf?
没错  我走了  约会要晚了
Right, got to go. Going to be late.
-约架子吗  -再见
- For a shelf? - Bye!
你看  这不还有别的玩伴陪你幺
There you go, you've got another playmate.
全宇宙也没几个人知道这号码
Hardly anyone in the universe has that number.
我就知道
Well, I'VE got it.
是商店里的某个女人给你的
Yes, from some woman in a shop.
我们仍然不知道她是谁
We STILL don't know who that was.
这是她打的吗
Is that her now?
反正只可能是极少的几个人之一
There are very few people that it could be.
-别接  -为什么
- Don't. - Why not?
-你一接  肯定会有事  -什么事
- Because, if you answer it, something will happen. - What?
反正有事
A thing.
只是一通电话而已  克拉拉
It's just a phone, Clara.
接个电话能有什么事
Nothing happens when you answer the phone.
-博士  -别碰那玩意
- Doctor? - Don't touch it!
我们在哪  怎么到这来了
Where are we? How did we get here?
你们是谁
Who are you?
抱歉这是怎么回事  我有点糊涂了
Sorry, what's going on? I don't understand.
-这是什么东西  -这是食忆虫
- What is that thing? - It's a memory worm.
你的脸刚才怎么了
What happened to your face?
它会吞噬你的记忆
Deletes your memories.
你刚看见她的脸了吗
Did you see her face?
我怎么到这来的
How did I get here?
显然跟我们一样  但我们全忘了
The same way we all did, but we've all forgotten.
您是哪位
And who are you?
我是博士  是来自伽里弗雷的时间领主
I am the Doctor, a Time Lord from Gallifrey.
我同意进行记忆抹除  且完全自愿
I have agreed to this memory wipe of my own free will.
我是克拉拉·奥斯瓦尔德  人类
I am Clara Oswald, human.
我同意进行记忆抹除  且完全自愿
I have agreed to this memory wipe of my own free will.
我非得摸这虫子吗
Do I really have to touch that worm thing?
非摸不可  把高跟鞋换了
Yes, you do. And change your shoes.
你是下一个  塞
You're next, Psi.
我是塞  我是改造人
I am Psi - augmented human.
我同意进行记忆抹除  且完全自愿
I have agreed to this...memory wipe of my own free will.
记忆已损坏
我是塞伯拉  变异人
I am Saibra - mutant human.
我同意进行记忆抹除  且完全自愿
I have agreed to this memory wipe of my own free will.
打雷章鱼X  连也
神秘嘟嘟  滚成一个Tardis
泰斯十英寸  七七
undottore  Reginamoon
人人影视英剧社倾情奉献
神秘博士
第八季  第五集
人人影视英剧社倾情奉献
神秘博士
第八季  第五集
人人影视英剧社倾情奉献
神秘博士
第八季  第五集
讷讷  宝宝
咖喱小焙  打雷章鱼X
这是一条预存信息
This is a recorded message.
我是筑梦师
I am the Architect.
你们记得的最后一件事
Your last memory is of
后期
宝宝
就是接到未知人士  也就是我打来的电话
receiving a contact from an unknown agency - me.
你们自那之后的一切记忆已被抹除
Everything since has been erased from your minds.
现在请仔细听情况介绍
Now, pay close attention to this briefing.
这里是卡拉布拉克索斯银行
This is the Bank of Karabraxos -
总监
吃货丁小七
全银河系最安全的银行
the most secure bank in the galaxy.
这里是巨富豪强的藏金堡垒
A fortress for the super-rich.
如果你买得起整个星系
If you can afford your own star system,
这里就是你存钱的好去处
this is where you keep it.
未经允许  任何人都别想踏上这星球一步
No-one sets foot on the planet without protocols.
一切行动都会受到监视
All movement is monitored,
连空气消耗都受到精确的控制
all air consumption regulated.
基因也要接受层层核查
DNA is authenticated at every stage.
入侵者将灰飞烟灭
Intruders will be incinerated.
所有金库都深藏地下
Each vault, buried deep in the earth,
存取物件都要通过地表的转存系统
is accessed by a drop-slot at the planet's surface.
整个金库配有原子封存
It's atomically sealed -
牢不可破  其序列已被彻底打乱
an unbreakable lock. The atoms have all been scrambled.
你们的到来未经许可
Your presence on this planet is unauthorised.
一支小队正赶来消灭你们
A team will have been despatched to terminate you.
我们是银行安保  马上开门
This is bank security! Open up!
你们想要活命  就必须听我指令
Your survival depends on following my instructions.'
立即开门  你们将被人道毁灭
Open up and you shall be humanely disposed of.
那边还有一个出口
There's another exit!
你们所需的一切信息都在这个箱子中
All the information you need is in this case.
-你在干什么  -下载
- What are you doing? - Downloading.
不愧是改造过的  非常好
Augmented - nice.
卡拉布拉克索斯银行固若金汤
The Bank of Karabraxos is impregnable.
请不要站在门口
Please stand away from the door!
我们不想在焚化前伤害到你们
We do not wish to hurt you before incineration.
卡拉布拉克索斯银行从未被入侵
The Bank of Karabraxos has never been breached.
而你们将抢劫卡拉布拉克索斯银行
You will rob the Bank of Karabraxos.
汇报情况
Report.
抱歉  你是哪位
Sorry, hello? Who is this?
我是德福克斯女士  银行安保主管
This is Ms Delphox - Head of Bank Security.
我派你们去调查来自外界的入侵者
I sent you to investigate an off-world intruder.
是吗  我还在想我们来这里做什么
Did you? I was wondering what we're doing here.
我们找到了一种神奇的虫子
We found these amazing worms...
有不速之客  我们需要读心者
Unwelcome guests. We're going to need the Teller.
你饿了吗  孩子
Are you hungry, boy?
行了  停下  够远了
OK, OK, OK. Stop, stop, stop. Far enough.
改造人  计算机改造的  对吧
Augmented human. Computer-augmented, yes?
-头脑里装有主机  -我是个职业玩家
- Mainframe in your head? - I'm a gamer.
不好意思  谁让你指挥了
Sorry, who put YOU in charge?
你在撒谎  你的脖子上纹有罪犯编号
You're a liar. That's a prison code on your neck.
我是个黑客  兼银行抢劫者
I'm a hacker...slash bank robber.
很好  今天正需要银行抢劫者
Good. This is a good day to be a bank robber.
变异人  哪种变异
Mutant human. What kind of mutant?
就像他说的  为什么现在你指挥
Like he says, why are YOU in charge now?
这是我的特殊能力  你的呢
It's my special power - what's yours?
我触摸活细胞  就能复制细胞的主人
I touch living cells - I can replicate the owner.
你的脸  我们最初见你时
Your face, when we first saw you...
我触摸了食忆虫
I touched the worm.
你也能复制他们的衣服吗
You can replicate their clothes too?
我穿着全息壳子
I wear a hologram shell.
人类细胞  应该是某个顾客的DNA
Human cells. DNA from a customer, maybe?
让我们进入银行的伪装
A disguise to get us in?
我们真的要抢劫银行吗
We're actually going to do it? Rob the bank?
我们别无选择  我们已经同意了
I don't think we have a choice - we've already agreed to.
你能保持这个形象多久
How long can you maintain the image for?
我愿意多久就能多久
For as long as I like.
问题一  有塔迪斯抢劫银行会很容易
Question one - robbing banks is easy if you've got a TARDIS.
我为什么不用
So why am I not using it?
问题二  塔迪斯在哪里
Question two, where IS the TARDIS?
好吧  这才应该是问题一
OK, that probably should be question one.
封锁银行大厅
Banking floor locking down.
他们知道我们来了
They know we're here.
封锁银行大厅
Banking floor locking down.
那是什么
What is that?
不知道  真讨厌不知道的感觉
I don't know. Hate not knowing.
打扰一下  先生
Excuse me, sir.
很遗憾地告知您已被探测出有罪恶感
I regret to say that your guilt has been detected.
什么  这太荒谬了
What? That... that's totally ridiculous.
是吗  先生  那么我们来再检查一次
Is it, sir? Well, then, we will certainly double-check.
读心者将会扫描出您的任何犯罪意图
The Teller will now scan your thoughts for any criminal intent.
祝您好运  先生
Good luck, sir.
-有意思  -什么有意思
- Interesting. - What is?
最新版的警犬
The latest thing in sniffer dogs.
心灵感应者  它能探测罪恶感
Telepathic - it hunts guilt.
那我们的罪恶感呢
What about OUR guilt?
暂时被淹没了
Currently being drowned out.
他在干什么
What's he doing?
如果他有犯罪计划  他在努力不想它
If he has a plan, he's trying NOT to think of it.
试过努力不想某件事吗
Ever tried not thinking about something?
-没有  -你可能要经历了
- No. - You may have to.
探测到了犯罪意图
Criminal intent detected.
真淘气  你的计划是什么
How naughty. What was your plan?
你的箱子里装的是伪币吗
Counterfeit currency in your briefcase, perhaps?
不  完全没有  求你了
No, not at all, for God's sake.
这不重要
It doesn't really matter,
细节我们稍后调查
we'll establish the details later.
读心者探测罪恶感时
The Teller is never wrong
从未出错
when it comes to guilt.
你的账户将被清除
Your account will now be deleted,
还有你的思想
and obviously your mind.
你可以吃晚饭了
Suppertime!
清除他的思想  把他的大脑变成汤
Wiping his mind - turning his brain into soup.
你的近亲将会被告知此事
Your next of kin will be informed,
并被监禁
and incarcerated,
作为对诚信金融交易的激励
as further inducement to honest financial transactions.
我们得帮帮他
We've got to help him.
他已经被清除了  一切都结束了
He's gone already, it's over.
他很痛苦  看看他
He's in agony, look at him.
那些不是眼泪  克拉拉  是汤
Those aren't tears, Clara. That's soup.
账户已结清
Account closed.
把他带走  他已经准备好被做成特写了
Take him away. He's ready for his close-up.
打扰大家  深感抱歉
Apologies for the disturbance.
祝大家过得愉快
Everyone have a lovely day.
封闭交易屋  请呼气
Deposit booth locking. Please exhale.
您的贵重物品将从金库运输上来
Your valuables will be transported up from the vault.
如果他能潜入这里并存入这个东西
If he can break in here and plant this thing,
他为什么还需要我们的帮助
then why does he need our help?
这取决于那个东西是什么
Depends what the thing is.
我不是专家  但是有雷管
OK, well, I'm no expert, but...fuses,
有计时器  我我敢打赌这是个炸弹
timer, I'm going to stick my neck out and say "Bomb".
银行图解  现在就要
Bank schematic...now.
所以我们在大厅抓到的人并不是目标人物
So, the man we captured on the banking floor wasn't the target.
四名访客刚进入一间安全交易屋
Four visitors just entered a safety-deposit box.
银河系最伟大的银行
The greatest bank in the galaxy.
我们的名誉不容玷污
Our reputation must remain secure.
行长会怪罪我们  我们会被开除的
The Director will blame us. We'll be fired...
非常痛苦的被开除
Fired with pain.
地板下面是服务通道
The floor below is all service corridors,
也是这个银行的命脉
the veins and arteries of the bank.
他想让我们炸开地板
He wants us to blow through the floor.
那样我们都会死的
We'll die if we do that.
不一定  肯定有什么计划
Well, not necessarily, there must be a plan.
如果计划就是我们要替别人炸开地板呢
What if the plan is, we're blowing up the floor for someone else?
如果计划就没打算让我们活命怎么办
What if we're not supposed to make it out alive?
别这幺悲观
Oh, don't be so...pessimistic,
这样会影响我们的士气
it'll affect team morale.
让我们全被炸飞就不影响士气了吗
What, and getting us blown up won't?
那个对士气影响非常小
Well, only very, very briefly.
不可能  你想怎么干随你
Er, no, no way! You can do what you like.
我宁可出去碰碰运气
I'm going to take my chances out there.
-赛  -不  不  不
- Psi! - No, no, no,
这家伙  你这伙计就是个疯子
this guy - your mate - is a lunatic!
你想要什么  赛  最想要什么
What do you want, Psi, more than anything else?
不管你要什么  它都在这个银行里
Whatever it is, it's in this bank.
你同意来抢劫这个史上最牢不可破的银行
You agreed to rob the most impregnable bank in history,
一定有非来不可的理由
you must have had a very good reason.
我们一定都有
We all must have.
想象一下宇宙中你最想得到的那个东西
Picture the thing you want most in the universe
看看你的愿望有多强烈
and decide how badly you want it.
想好了吗
Well?
我还是不明白为什么要听你指挥
Still don't understand why you're in charge.
应该是因为我的眉毛
Basically, it's the eyebrows.
很好
Nice.
空间转移炸弹
Dimensional shift bomb.
可以将粒子传送至另一个平面
Sends the particles to a different plane.
来吧
Come on, then.
全队存活
Team Not Dead!
开门
Open up!
我们现在该怎么办
Well, so, what are we supposed to do now?
计划是什么
What's the plan?
我不知道  筑梦师策划这一切
I don't know. The Architect set all this up,
肯定有他的道理
it should make sense.
我个人的计划认为很快就会有事情发生
My personal plan is that a thing will probably happen quite soon.
-当然了  这就是你的计划吗  -没错
- So that's it. That's your plan? - Yep.
有事会发生
A thing will happen?
可能有事发生
A thing...probably.
赛
Hey, Psi!
博士
Doctor!
走吧  事件时间到
There you go! Thing time!
他怎么把箱子放在这里的
How does he get the cases here?
在入侵银行前先入侵一次
By breaking into the bank in advance of breaking into the bank.
他是怎么做到的
How did he do that?
如果他一个人就行  还要我们做什么
And if he CAN do that, why does he need us?
那不是我们的问题
Not our problem.
那什么是我们的问  问  问  问
What is our prob-prob-prob-prob...?
-你没事吧  -驱动出了点故障  没事
- You OK? - Drive glitch, it's fine.
罪恶感才是我们的问题
Guilt is our problem.
在这家银行里  罪恶感足以致命
Guilt, in this bank, is fatal.
读心者可以听到
The Teller can hear it.
从打开第一个箱子起  我们就被盯上了
Ever since that first case was opened, we've been targets.
我们越清楚自己来这里的原因
The more we know about why we're here,
我们的罪恶感发出的声响就越大
the louder our guilt screams.
出于安全考虑  我们一定要抹去记忆
That's why we wiped our memories for our own safety.
一旦我打开这个箱子  就再也关不上了
Now, once I open this, I can't close it again.
要是我们当中只有一人知道  会不会安全些
Would it be safer if only one of us learned it?
我在等你自告奋勇
I'm waiting for you to volunteer.
为什么是我
Why me?
因为你不需要食忆虫  不是吗
Because you didn't need that memory worm, did you?
你一半是计算机  可以自己动手删除
You're half-computer, you can perform a manual delete.
你可以清空你的记忆
You CAN clear your thoughts.
我不知道这是什么  也许你该来看一下
I don't know what it is. You may as well have a look.
这是什么
Well, what are they?
-不知道  -真有意思
- Not a clue. - Hmm, interesting.
怎么了
What is?
你在撒谎
You're lying.
你为什么要撒  撒  撒  撒谎
Er, why would he be lyi-lyi-lyi-lying?
抱歉  太紧张了  电池消耗太快
Sorry. Stress. Drains the batteries.
-接上这个  -我们还有时间弄这个吗
- Interface with this. - Do we have time for this?
为什么没有  目前还没有什么威胁
Why not? There's no immediate threat.
警告  发现入侵者
Warning. Intruders detected.
我不该那么说
I should stop saying things like that.
发现入侵者
Intruders detected.
克拉拉  你和赛在一起  塞伯拉
Clara, stay with Psi. Saibra...
咱们去侦察一下
let's go and investigate.
发现...
Intru...
清理尘土
Storm dust.
你真的可以删除自己的记忆吗
You can delete your memories?
是的  不过并不像听起来那么好玩
Yeah, it's not as fun as it sounds.
我倒是有些希望丢掉的记忆
I've got a few I wish I could lose.
我丢掉了许多不想丢掉的记忆
And I've lost a few I wish I hadn't.
我在狱中受审
No, I was...I was interrogated in prison.
我想我一定太害怕了
And I guess I panicked.
我不想让我亲近的人有危险
I didn't want to be a risk to the people close to me, so...
你删去了对朋友的记忆吗
You deleted your friends?
朋友  所有帮助过我的人  还有家人
My friends, anyone who ever helped me, my family.
-你的家人  -是的  我的家人
- Your family? - Of course, my family.
你怎么做到的
How could you do that?
我也不知道
Well, I don't know.
我觉得我一定非常爱他们
I suppose I must have loved them.
严禁进入
你不是要问我吗
Aren't you going to ask me?
你为什么撒谎  你知道那些东西是什么
Why did you lie? Those  things, you know what they are.
某种退路
Exit strategy, of sorts.
你怎么知道我在撒谎的
How did you know I was lying?
我经常换面孔  我发现它们很容易读懂
I've had a lot of faces, I find them easy to read.
-真是个有用的天赋  -天赋
- Quite a gift. - Gift?!
让我们来到这里
Got us in here.
变异基因  没人能碰我
Mutant gene. No-one can touch me.
如果他们碰了  我就会变形
If they do, I transform.
碰我一下博士  然后你就看到了你自己
Touch me, Doctor, and you'll be looking at yourself.
我只能孤独一人
I am alone!
-为什么  -你能信任一个
- Why? - Could you trust someone
用你自己的眼睛回看你的人吗
who looked back at you out of your own eyes?
天吶
Oh, my God.
-他为什么还活着  -我不知道
- Why is he even still alive? - I don't know.
但有人在监视
But someone is watching.
博士
Doctor.
无论如何  不管发生了什么
However this goes, whatever happens...
不要让我落到那样的下场
Don't let me end up like that.
入侵者在服务层
Intruders on the service level.
严禁进入
这提示代表这是个藏身之处
Now, this says, "Place to hide."
我们在哪里
Where are we?
所有人别动  一个字都别说
Nobody move. Nobody say a word.
它被隔离了
It's cocooned.
强制休眠
Forced hibernation.
它的力量很可能处于休眠状态
Its power is probably dormant.
克拉拉  它锁定你了
Clara! It's locked on to you.
-它也许还在休眠  别弄醒它  -好
- It may still be asleep, don't wake it. - OK.
我怎么才不会弄醒它
How do I not do that?
什么也别想
Keep your mind blank.
屏蔽一切思想
Block everything.
它一旦锁定了你的思想就不会放手
Once it locks onto your thoughts, it won't let go.
它正在醒来
It's waking up.
屏蔽你的思想  克拉拉
Keep blocking your thoughts, Clara.
别思考
Don't think.
这边
This way!
塞伯拉
Saibra!
她还在里面  怎么救她出来
She's still in there. How do we get her out?
-它在扫描她的大脑  -然后会怎样
- It's scanning her brain. - Then what?!
-变成汤  -那就帮帮她
- Soup! - Then help her!
塞伯拉
Saibra!
我该做什么  我该怎么逃
What should I do? How can I get away?
它正在彻查你的大脑
It's rooting through your brain.
它正在品尝里面存着的所有秘密
It's tasting all the secrets stashed inside.
它随时都可能结束扫描
Any moment now, it will finish its sweep
开始享受余下的部分
and start feasting on what's left.
然后我就变成我们看到的那些笼中之物吗
And then I become one of those things we saw, sitting in a cage!
-对  -你能不能把我弄出去
- Yes. - Can you not get me out?
抱歉  一旦它锁定了你的思想
I'm sorry. I don't know how,
我就不知该怎么办了
once it's locked onto your thoughts.
那所谓的退路
Exit strategy.
它就是我想的那种意思  对不对
That means what I think it means, right?
-原子粉碎机  -无痛吗
- Atomic shredder. - Painless?
而且实时起效
And instant.
当你见到筑梦师的时候  向我保证
When you meet the Architect, promise me something.
杀了他
Kill him.
我恨他  但我不能作出这承诺
I hate him, but I can't make that promise.
你是一个好人  我遇见得太晚了
A good man... I left it late to meet one of those.
好  地下金库  目标很清楚
Right, vault, that's clear.
我们不清楚的是我们现在做什么
What's not clear is what we do now.
你还好吗
You OK?
不  我是抢银行的失忆者
No, I'm an amnesiac robbing a bank,
我为什么会没事呢
why would I be OK?
-因为赛伯拉  -什么
- Because Saibra... - What?
赛伯拉死了而我们还活着
Saibra is dead, we are alive -
如果你想活下去就要知道孰轻孰重
prioritise if you want to stay that way.
所以你才自称博士对吗
Oh, is THAT why you call yourself the Doctor -
专业超然之人
the professional detachment?
听着  当我们干完这票  随便你
Listen, when we're done here, by all means,
给自己找个肩膀痛哭一场
you go and find yourself a shoulder to cry on.
你很有可能会有这个需要
You'll probably need that.
但在那之前  你需要我
Till then, what you need is me!
在这些表象下面  他其实不是那样的人
Underneath it all, he isn't really like that.
很明显你和他已经一起行动一段时间了
It's very obvious that you've been with him for a while.
为什么
Why?
因为你真得很会找借口
Because you are really good at the excuses.
另一个来自筑梦师的礼物
Another gift from the Architect.
我们该打开它吗
Shall we unwrap it?
牢不可破的银行
The unbreakable bank.
我们必须找到他们
We must locate them.
卡拉布拉克索斯行长不能知道这件事
And Director Karabraxos must not know.
在这里  人们被开除的时候
When people get fired here...
会很糟糕
it's messy.
把读心者放入隧道
Release the Teller into the tunnels.
好  系统看上去象是被延时了
Right, the system looks like it's time-delayed.
我需要破解24道密码锁
There are 24 lock codes I need to break.
博士  它来了  我们被困住了
Doctor...it's coming. We're trapped.
-赛  需要多久  -有多久就要多久
- Psi, how long? - As long as it takes.
他锁定我们中一个人的思维踪迹了
It's locked on to one of our thought trails.
我们必须分开  减弱大脑信号
We have to split up, minimise the brain signals.
你的超然态度呢  博士
What happened to your professional detachment, Doctor?
不  不要
No, no!
以防我被发现  这是我的选择
In case it finds me. It's my choice.
千万别用  好吗  答应我
You don't use that, OK? Promise me.
该跑了
Time to run.
分开跑
Separate!
金库正在打开
'Vault box opening.
24  23  22  21
'24, 23, 22, 21,
20  19  18  17
'20, 19, 18, 17...'
清空你的思想  克拉拉
Keep your mind clear, Clara.
什么也别想
Keep your mind blank.
-啊  -克拉拉
- Aggh! - Clara!
来啊
Come on!
来找我啊
Come and find me.
闪现的恶人包括  斯力辛家族[S01E04-05]  冰雪战士[S07E08]  "枪手"[S07E03]
所有的飞贼和恶棍都在这儿了
Every thief and villain in one big cocktail.
Terileptil[老版S19E04-08]  "骗子"  "身体掠夺者"Androvax[详见《莎拉·简大冒险》]
我真是罪大恶极
I am so guilty!
历史上所有的江洋大盗  此时都藏在银行里
Every famous burglar in history is hiding in this bank right now
寄身在一具躯壳中
in one body!
来饱餐一顿吧
Go and feast!
克拉拉
Clara!
这幺说吧  先不管是真是假
For what it's worth - and it might not be worth much -
当你的整个人生在眼前闪现
when your whole life flashes in front of you,
你会看到你爱的人
you see people you love...
看到想念你的人
and people missing you...
我呢  谁也看不到
Well, I see no-one.
3  2  1
'Three, two, one...
失败  金库解锁  失败
'Failed. Vault unlocking. Failed.'
没有打开
It's not opening!
赛
Psi...
他白白牺牲了
He died for nothing.
多重封锁
Multiple locks.
最后一个没有打开
Last one still in place.
原子密封  打不开
Atomic seal. Unbreakable.
我也不行
Even for me.
筑梦师应该知道
The Architect would know that.
否则他不会白白送我们进来
He wouldn't bring us all this way for nothing.
还害两个人送命
And get two people killed.
正是
Exactly.
这当中肯定有什么逻辑
There must be some logic.
逻辑
Some logic?
来吧  筑梦师  你还有什么牌
Come on, Architect! What else have you got?
请汇报  这干扰是怎么回事
Report, please. What was the disturbance?
太阳风暴曾在S06E05中出现
太阳风暴  越来越凶猛了
Solar storm. Getting worse.
影响了我们的系统
Interfering with our systems.
风暴
A storm...
风暴扰乱了系统
The storm's tripping the system.
这就是他手里的牌  风暴
That's what he's got - a storm!
他怎么知道风暴何时发生
How would he know WHEN a storm would hit?
当然
Of course!
愚蠢的博士啊
Stupid, stupid Doctor.
-当然当然  -什么当然
- Of course, of course! - Of course, what?
无论谁计划了这一切  他们身处未来
Whoever planned all this, they're in the future.
这不是简单的银行抢劫
This isn't just a bank heist...
而是一次时空大劫案
It's a time-travel heist.
我们被送到
We've been sent back in time
风暴发生的时点
to the exact moment of the storm,
灾难到来的地点
to be in exactly the right place when it hits,
只有在这个时点  银行是可以攻破的
because that's the only time the bank is vulnerable!
金库打开
'Vault unlocked.'
银行现在开了
The bank is now open!
金库打开
'Vault unlocked.'
这就清楚了  为何我们听不见塔迪斯
It explains why we're not hearing the TARDIS.
-什么  -太阳风暴的破坏
- Sorry, what? - The solar disruption
阻断了宇宙航行的可能性
would have made navigation impossible.
银行最脆弱的时候
The one time the bank is vulnerable
正是我们没法着陆的时候
is the one time we can't just land.
博士  号码
Doctor...the code!
最后一个箱子里的号码  看
The code that was in the last case. Look.
-科技  -科技
- Tech. - Technology.
251  去找
251. Find it.
科技
Tech.
这是初始化回路
It's a neophyte circuit.
我以前只见过一次
I've only ever seen one once before.
它可以重启任何系统  恢复丢失的数据
It can reboot any system. Replace any lost data.
赛
Psi...
这是他来这里的目的  他的回报
That's what he came for - his reward.
那么塞伯拉来是为什么
So what did Saibra come for?
基因抑制剂
Gene suppressant.
-她想成为普通人  -人人都有弱点
- She wanted to be normal. - Everyone has a weakness.
最后的问题是  我们来是为什么
So the big question is this - what did we come for?
-PV  -私人金库
- PV... - Private vault.
卡拉布拉克索斯本人的财富吗
Karabraxos's own fortune?
德福克斯女士
我最喜欢入侵者了
Intruders are most welcome.
他们提醒我这座银行固若金汤
They remind us that the bank is impregnable.
有几个你们这样的人
It's good for morale to
关在这里  有助于鼓舞士气
have a few of you scattered about the place,
也更具观赏性
preferably on view.
准备好迎接你自己的大特写了吗
Are you ready for YOUR close-up?
如果你在思考怎么逃跑
If you're thinking of ways to escape,
你还没来得及行动  读心者就会知道
the Teller will know before you've even made a move.
你也就再也不会被这些念头困扰了
You'll never be bothered by all that thinking again.
多么有用的物种
Useful species.
最后一只了  和我们做了独家交易
Last of its kind, and we've signed an exclusive deal.
它的脑袋里一定吵翻了天
Must be noisy inside its head.
听这幺多唠叨一定很痛苦
Painful to listen to so much chatter,
这幺多秘密
so many secrets...
一定快要把它逼疯了
must drive it wild.
你们是如何强迫它屈服的
How can you force it to obey?
任何事都可以明码标价  你会知道的
Oh, everything has a price tag, I think you'll find.
太阳风暴越来越猛烈了
The storm's getting worse.
顾客们开始离开  卡拉布拉克索斯行长
Customers are leaving. Director Karabraxos will soon be...
很快就会察觉了  我们的工作要不保了
concerned. Our jobs will be on the line.
你害怕了
You're scared.
我怕死了
Oh, I'm terrified.
很不幸我认识卡拉布拉克索斯本人
I have the disadvantage of knowing Karabraxos personally.
如果不喜欢你的老板  为何还留在这里
If you don't like your boss, why stay?
我的脸适合这份工作
My face fits.
如果你不介意的话
Now...if you'll excuse me,
我要带读心者去休眠了
I must take the Teller to its hibernation.
你们两个  把客人处理掉
You two, dispose of our guests.
别这样  我今天过得很糟糕
Don't do this. I'm having a very bad day,
-我不想任人摆布  -你错了
- and I do not want to be pushed around. - You're wrong.
错了
Wrong?
今天也没那么糟糕
It's not that bad a day.
而且你们动作太慢了
And you're being very slow.
你为什么解开我的手铐
Why are you undoing my handcuffs?
塞伯拉
Saibra?
看起来象是死了
It LOOKED like death.
-事实上是被瞬间传送了  -太好了
- It was actually a teleporter. - Oh, my God!
不错吧  你以为我们死了
Good, eh? You think we're dead,
所以读心者也会这幺以为
so the Teller thinks we're dead,
我们在它的大脑里跟它捉迷藏
and we play the creature at his own mind games.
不  不  等等  等等
No, no, wait, wait, wait, wait!
什么  抱歉  什么
What? Sorry, sorry, what?
你们  你们  你们还活着
You, you, you're...you're alive?
没错  我们还活着  我们都还活着
Yeah, we're alive. Look at us, we're all alive.
不  不  不  不是死了
No, no, no, no. Not dead.
-而是还活着  -轨道上有一艘逃生船
- Alive. - There's an escape ship in orbit.
这个会把你直接送到那里
Takes you right there.
对了  那儿还有个
Oh, and there's this
巨大的蓝箱子  是你的吗
big blue box - is that yours?
很好
Well, this is good...
我想
I suppose...
你们可以继续执行任务了
You'll be able to resume the mission.
基因抑制剂  你的解药
Gene suppressant - antidote for your condition.
记忆恢复仪
Memory giver.
重拾你往日的记忆
All your yesterdays.
好了  任务完成  报酬结清
There you go. Job done, paid in full.
-筑梦师真是个聪明的老家伙  -非常聪明
- Clever old Architect. - Very clever.
-但我还是恨他  -我也是
- I still hate him. - Me too.
你的报酬又是什么
How are you paid?
我不知道
I don't know.
还有些东西在私人金库里
There's something in the private vault.
-那是什么  -输气管道
- What's that? - Supply line.
唯一一条给私人金库供氧的通道
It's the only oxygen down to the private vault.
还有另一条供水的
There's another one for water
来提供基础生命支持
for basic life support.
什么  为了一个私人金库
What, for a private vault?
有人就喜欢和他们的财产守在一起
Someone likes to hang out with their wealth.
莫扎特《后宫诱逃》序曲
卡拉布拉克索斯行长
Director Karabraxos?
不好意思  但我们是来抢劫你的
Excuse us, but we've come to rob you.
所以如果你愿意把手举过头顶  或者
So if you want to put your hands above your head, or...
或者怎样
Or?
你们又没带武器
You didn't bring any weapons.
有点小失误啊
That's a bit of an oversight.
安保部门  我是卡拉布拉克索斯行长
Security, Karabraxos here.
-你是卡拉布拉克索斯  -稍等
- You're Karabraxos? - One moment.
卡拉布拉克索斯行长
Director Karabraxos,
有什么问题吗
is there a problem?
有入侵者闯入了我的私人金库
Intruders in the private vault.
把读心者送过来
Send me the Teller.
我要找出他们是如何进来的
I want to find out how they got in,
然后抹去他们的记忆
and then I want to wipe their memories.
她是个克隆人
She's a clone.
这是保证我个人安全的唯一方式
It's the only way to control my own security.
我在每个部门都有个克隆人
I have a clone in every facility.
-马上把它送过来  -当然
- Get on it right away. - Yes, of course.
然后把你的证件交上来
And then hand in your credentials.
你被解雇了  立即生效
You're fired, with immediate effect.
可是我已经尽心竭力服务您
But, please, I've been in your service...
你的前任让我失望  害我不得不杀掉它
Ever since the last one let me down and I was forced to kill it.
我不敢相信你竟然又把我置于这种境地
I can't quite believe that you're putting me through this again.
我的克隆人  她甚至没有抗议
My clone. And yet she doesn't even protest.
真是拙劣的仿制品
Pale imitation, really.
-我真该起诉克隆公司  -你要杀了她
- I should sue! - You're killing her?
-但你刚才说...  -解雇吗
- You just said... - Fired?
我把所有用过的克隆体扔进焚烧炉里
I put all of the used clones into the incinerator.
不能让那么多我到处跑
Can't have too many of moi scattered around.
不好意思  你和自己的克隆体处不来
Sorry, you don't get on with your own clone?
她恨自己的克隆体
She hates her own clones,
她烧掉自己的克隆体
she burns her own clones.
你是心理医生梦寐以求的案例
Frankly, you're a career break for the right therapist.
闭嘴  所有人  都给我  闭嘴
Shut up. Everybody, just...just shut up!
你又在唱哪出跟你一样滑稽的戏码
And what is this display now, as amusing as you are?
闭嘴  给我闭嘴  闭闭嘴嘴嘴
Shut up! Just shut up, shut up, shut up, shutetty up up up!
你  你刚才说了什么
What...what did you say?
你刚才  说了什么
What did...you say?
关于自己眼睛  你说了什么来着
What did you say... about your own eyes?
取消闭嘴  再说一遍
De-shut up, say it again.
你能信任一个
How can you trust someone
用你自己的眼睛回看你的人吗
if they look back at you out of your own eyes?
关于筑梦师  我知道一点
I know one thing about the Architect.
关于筑梦师我知道什么
What is it that I know about the Architect?
有一件事  一件从开始就知道的事
I know one thing, something I've known from the very start.
-什么  -我恨他
- What? - I hate him.
他专横霸道  他是操纵狂
He's overbearing, he's manipulative,
他自以为聪明过人  我恨他
he likes to think that he's very clever. I HATE him.
克拉拉  还不明白吗
Clara, don't you see?
我恨筑梦师
I hate the Architect!
这是一屋子的疯子吗
What in the name of sanity is going in this room now?
连自己都烧的人还好意思说我们疯了
We're getting sanity judgment from the self-burner.
介意我借张纸吗
Do you mind if I borrow a little bit of paper?
你在搞什么鬼
And what are you doing now?
我要给你
I'm giving you...
我的电话号码
my telephone number.
为什么
Why?
因为
Well,
也许你哪天想给我打电话
I thought you might like to call me someday.
我是时间旅行者
抱歉  我还以为你我相处得挺和睦呢
Sorry, I thought we were getting along famously -
我是时间旅行者
还是我看错您脸色了
am I, like, misreading the signals or something?
这次风暴真强  对吧
Oh, that was a big one, wasn't it?
你的银行怕要永远关门了  卡拉布拉克索斯
I think that your bank is about to close for good, Karabraxos.
换作是我  我就会快点跑
If I was you, I'd get going.
别担心我们  我们就在这等着被烧掉
Don't mind us, we'll just stay here and burn.
不知道该带什么是吧
Hard to know what to take.
把全宇宙最珍贵的财富塞进一个小箱子
The greatest treasures of the universe in just one suitcase.
博士  计划是什么  到底有没有计划
Doctor, what's the plan? IS there a plan?
我们可以用原子粉碎机回到飞船上
We can use the shredders, get back to the ship.
它们不是原子粉碎机  是瞬间传送仪
They're not shredders, they're teleports,
这还不是它们最有趣的地方
and that's not the most interesting thing about them.
-那是什么  -一共有六个
- So what is? - There were six of them.
记得打给我
Give me a call me some time.
门开启
Doors opening.
你会死的
You'll be dead.
你会老的  我们真合拍
Yeah, you'll be old - we'll get on famously.
你会变老
You'll be old and full of
对无法更改的事充满悔恨
regret for the things that you can't change.
门关闭
Doors closing.
-博士到底发生了什么  -你记忆恢复了
- Doctor, what the hell is going on? - Are you remembering?
没  一点也没有
No, not a thing.
不过我明白了
But I'm understanding.
什么  你明白什么了
What is it? What are you understanding?
我还不确定
I'm not sure yet.
我要找回记忆
I need my memory back.
只有一个办法可行
And I think there is only one way to do that...
什么办法
Which would be?
-脑汤  -脑汤
- Soup. - Soup?
你好  大家伙
Hello, big man.
-饿了吗  -博士
- Peckish? - Doctor!
不不  让他看到我的思维
No...no, let it take me.
读取我的记忆  这是唯一的办法
Let it read me. It's the only way!
-它会杀了你的  -我就说你太悲观
- It will kill you! - What have I told you about pessimism?
对  就是这样
Right, that's it...
这里有这幺多记忆
There are so many memories in here.
吃吧
Feast on them.
尽情吃吧
Tuck in.
大围巾[第四任]  领结[十一任]
Big scarf, bow tie,
有点丢人
bit embarrassing.
新面孔怎么样
What do you think of the new look?
我想要张大众脸
I was hoping for minimalism,
结果长得太有特点
but I think I came up with magician!
在最近几天  有一段记忆被屏蔽了
In the last few days, there's been a block.
你能破除屏蔽吗
Can you see the block?
告诉我  我为什么在这
Tell me why I'm here!
Show me why I'm here!
告诉我
Show me!
就一通电话而已  克拉拉
It's just a phone, Clara.
接个电话能有什么事
Nothing happens when you answer the phone.
博士
Doctor?
你好
Hello?
你给了我这号码  我是卡拉布拉克索斯女士
You gave me this number. My name is Madame Karabraxos.
我曾经...
I was once...
是宇宙中最富有的人
the wealthiest person in the Universe.
我需要你的帮助
I need your assistance.
我命不久矣
I'm dying.
心中却有许多遗憾
With many, many regrets...
但是有一个...也许...
but one...perhaps...
你可以帮到我
you may be able to help me with.
我们得小小地绕一下路了
It's a little detour.
有个活儿  我得帮某人个忙  来吧
It's a job, I've got to do it for someone. Come on.
-我们要抢劫一家银行  -什么
- We need to rob a bank. - What?
克拉拉  我需要食忆虫
Clara, I need worms.
卡拉布拉克索斯银行从来没被攻破过
The Bank of Karabraxos has never been breached.
手动删除
筑梦师
Architect.
你将要抢劫卡拉布拉克索斯银行
You will rob the Bank of Karabraxos.
你有没有看见...
Did you see...
我们为什么而来
Why we came?
我们为什么会在这里
Why we're here?
我们得把自己的记忆删除了
We had to delete our own memories,
不然的话你就会知道
otherwise you'd have known,
然后她也会知道  因为你俩心灵相通
and then she'd have known. Because you're mentally linked.
但现在她已经走了  他们都走了
But she's gone now. They've ALL gone.
你不再受制于他们了
They have no power over you now.
你现在想做什么都可以了
You can do exactly what you want to do now.
你可以做自己一直想做的事了
Exactly what you've always wanted to do.
它知道密码
It knows the combination!
它当然知道了
Of course it does,
它和卡拉布拉克索斯是心灵相通的
it was linked to Karabraxos.
我们到底在这儿干什么呢
What exactly are we doing here?
那东西杀了人
That thing killed people.
说不定你也会这幺做的
So might you do,
只为了保护自己所爱的一切
to protect everything you loved.
她在这儿
There she is.
这不是这个种族的最后一人
Not the last of its species.
而是最后一对
The last TWO.
没事了  她很好  没事了
It's OK, it's OK. It's all right.
撤离战略  我们有六个粉碎机
Exit strategy. We've got six shredders.
没错
Exactly!
这不是一次银行抢劫  从来都不是
This wasn't a bank heist - it never was.
这是一次救援任务  为了拯救整个种族
It was rescue mission, for a whole species.
血肉之躯  最后的货币
Flesh and blood - the last currency.
是时候回家了
Time to go home.
你意下如何  大个子
What do you think of that, big man?
宇宙中有如此多的精神旅行
So much mental traffic in the universe.
孤独是唯一的宁静
Solitude is the only peace.
乔弗雷·波吉亚
Gioffre Borgia
那个被称为"极端可怕之人"的人
mucho scary hombre
问我  "你觉得我们的比萨斜塔怎样"
says to me, "What do you think of our Leaning Tower of Pisa?"
我说"我看着还行"
I say, "It looks OK to me!"
你下次还需要人帮你抢银行  就叫我
If you ever need help with another bank heist...
他不太适合这个行当
Yeah, it's not really his area.
瞧  我现在没有复制你的样貌
See? I don't have your face now!
-是啊  我还有点怀念呢  -闭嘴
- Yeah. I kind of miss that. - Oh, shut up!
7月12日  当地时间  我保证过的
7.12, local time, as promised.
去好好放松一下吧
Go and enjoy yourself.
别做什么出格的事儿
Don't do anything I wouldn't do.
只是个约会而已
It's a date!
我刚刚意识到
I've just realised.
我现在要出去再吃一顿了
I'm going out for another meal now!
别担心
Don't worry.
在塔迪斯里摄取的热量不会让你变胖
Calories consumed on the Tardis have no lasting effect.
什么
What?
你在逗我呢吧
Are you kidding?!
当然是在逗你啦
Of course I'm kidding.
那只是个时间机器  不是奇迹创造机
It's a time machine, not a miracle-worker!
-拜拜  -再见  别去抢银行
- Bye! - See you. Don't rob any banks.
后面还有没说完的话吧
"Don't rob any banks" What?
带上我再去抢
Without me.
当然不会  老大
Course not, boss.
抢银行  抢了一整个银行
Robbing a bank! Robbing a whole bank!
还有比这更刺激的约会吗
Beat that for a date!
下回预告
你没事吧
Are you OK?
当然没事  为什么会有事
Yeah, course I'm OK. Why wouldn't I be OK?
我不知道  每次见到你  你都...
I don't know. Every time I see you, it's like you're...
怎么
What?
急匆匆的  心慌意乱
In a rush. In a state.
你好吗  抱歉我迟到了
How's you? Sorry I'm late!
你要和谁共进晚餐
Who are you having dinner with?
我不能一直这幺做  我做不到
I can't keep doing this. I can't do it.
接下来的几天都围着你转  我保证
The next few days are all about you. I promise.
我是新来的管理员  约翰·史密斯
I'm the new caretaker. John Smith.
欢迎来到科尔山  史密斯先生
Welcome to Cole Hill, Mr Smith.
谢谢
Thanks.
发现问题  解决方案  毁灭
Problem. Solution. Destroy.